Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise one hundred and eight.
So in this exercise, we are going to implement the Prem's algorithm in Java.
So how to do that?
We go to the algorithms package and we create in Java class.
And this Java class I recall as bring.
Rims are pretty secret, so.
I will start by making public void from.
Al Gore, it thick into the perimeter there due to the array.
And it's the first vertex, no what to do.
We start by making infinity equal to nine nine nine nine nine nine nine and end number of edges
equal to.
We don't we don't need to initialize it.
This is that number of each school initialize it later as zeros and start by taking into the perimeter.
The number offers distances and calculate edges.
So we create an array to track selected vertex and selected vertex will become true, otherwise false.
So what we will do here first create an array to track selected evacuates
Boolean Array Select called Selected Equal to New Boolean,
and we set the selected falls in the selected false initially, so we make the use of arrays.
This is the arrays which is in Java so we can import it alpha plus enter.
So this is Java, that utility arrays package.
We have imported it because we need to use make use of a function called sort, or we can make it as
full.
We can use the fill.
So I need to fill the selected with everything as as false.
OK.
No, set the number of edges equal to zero.
I would make it as here.
Number of edges equal to zero.
We are enclosing every step now.
The step number two, the number of edges in the minimum spanning tree will be always less than v minus
one.
So number of edges and minimum spanning
three less than.
All less than the minus one.
Okay, where is the number of vertices in the graph?
So choose their zeros zero zero vertex and make it through.
So selected.
This is the first index which is zero equal to true.
No.
Brent, the for edge and wait, so how to make it think.
Or we can make it with a system that out there to prevent an.
Adds, And we put weight.
OK.
So while we start making and testing number of edges less than a v minus one.
This is the condition that we have talked about here.
So number of edges and minimum spanning tree is always less than three minus one.
So why is this condition is true for every vertex in set s?
Find all the adjacent vertices and calculate the distance from the vertex selected at step one.
So if the vertex is already in the set s this guard, is it otherwise choose another vertex nearest
to the selected vertex at that point.
So what we will do, we will make here
int minimum equal to infinity and int x equal to zero and Y equal to zero.
This is the round number and this is the column number.
Number four and I equal to zero by less than a v i + plus.
What we will do, we need to check if it is selected.
If selected at index ie equal equal to true, then what we will do.
We will make a new loop that go through all the adjacent vertices and check for its existence.
And if we can contact them and we go through it by checking the minimum distance.
So how to do that by making a nested loop?
Also checking a v AJ less than V and J Plus plus
not selected and there is an edge.
So here we check for that condition now, not in selected array and there is an ad so F does not equal
to selected.
Appendix J.
And G at Index G.
Grant.
Selected at Index J and the G at index.
Oops!
At index here and the eye and index, Jane does not equal to zero.
So
if the minimum is greater than.
G at Index AI and Index J.
What we will do, we will make here.
Minimum equal to G at index AI and Index J here and X equal to AI and Y equal to J.
So we scroll down here and we exit from all the loops and we will right here and try to print out,
test them out.
Print L n x plus.
We will make that a condition here.
We will get all the variables.
And here we will have glass.
Here is the index of G Index AI and Index Edge Sorting Index X and Index Y.
OK.
And we put the selected at Index Y equal to true and number of edges + +.
If we check if there's a higher number of matches, I think.
I think it is outside the loop.
Yes, outside the loop ops.
So I will cut this.
I will move it outside the loop wire loop here.
And I will base that here.
OK.
Sorry.
I will put it here.
OK, so it is inside the wire loop, not this far.
You see, guys, while loop foot inside it enlisted for a loop and inside the for loop at this forward
loop.
Another forward.
OK.
We'll talk about the complexity in the next couple of minutes.
Now let's test a public static void main string index.
And here are the arcs.
We start by creating an instance from this class of prayer print.
Be equal to new frame
number of edges we will create and a graph number of edges equal to five and create a 2D array of size
five times five for adjacency matrix to represent that graph.
So I post a video and create this.
So this is our adjacency matrix representing the graph just through the array relay race and I will
call G Dot Premium or Premium G Dot or Prempeh Dot, Algo G and Z.
Passing this and calling this method in order to find that Jewish sentiment.
For this adjacency matrix, OK, where is the Earth?
New Boolean, new Boolean.
Let's see if there is a new Boolean array here, I think is for that inside the initialization.
Number of bullion would be equal to the first two seasons now.
OK.
Let's run here.
Run Prem's.
And here we go, guys, you see the edge and the weight.
Zero two one nine one two three one nine three two, four, three, one and three to two.
There's five what and this is that algorithm implemented and job.
So I want from you to write this code down and test it inside your inside your compiler.
And by the way, this this complexity complexity.
Here it is.
Oh, log e log v OK.
This is the complexity of the prince algorithm.
OK, because V is the number of vertices and is the number of edges.
OK.
So Prince algorithm can be used in laying cables of electrical wiring in network design and to make
protocols in network cycles.
So for this, we have finished this Prem's algorithm.
It's a gritty algorithm.
And let's.